Guide to the Robert S. and Eloise C. Wickham papers, 1776-1988.
Wickham, Robert S. and Eloise C. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert S. and Eloise C. Wickham papers, 1776-1988.
8408
Wickham, Robert Sloane,
3.6 cubic feet.
Bound manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, printed material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carpenter-Mayhew papers include correspondence, pamphlets, photographs, legal and estate papers, photographs, and clippings relating to Alvin R. Carpenter, Alice Carpenter, Charles Mayhew, Eloise Carpenter Wickham, and Robert Sloane Wickham. Charles Mayhew Carpenter papers include personal and business correspondence, 1910-1918, including letters from his estranged wife Mary.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert Sloane Wickham was born at Ballston Spa on March 14, 1877. He graduated from Saratoga Springs High School, studied law in the office of Babcock, sperry, and Van Cleve in Binghamton and attended Binghamton High School. In 1897, he won a state scholarship to Cornell and graduated in 1902 with a Bachelor of Law degree. In 1905 he married Eloise Cameron Carpenter. In 1908 they returned to Schuylerville, where he opened a law practice. In 1911, they went back to Binghamton when he was offered a junior partnership with the Chief Counsel of the Excise Department of New York State. He was an avid hiker and wrote two books, Friendly Adirondack Peaks and A Saratoga Boyhood (illustrated by Anne Allaben).
Eloise Cameron Carpenter was born in in Schuylerville, N.Y., the daughter of Alvin Rich Carpenter and Alida Catherine Mayhew. Alida Mayhew was the daughter of Charles Wadsworth Mahew and Maria DeRidder. Maria was the daughter of Walter DeRidder and Alida Vandenburgh. Walter DeRidder was the son of Simon DeRidder, a Brigadier General during the War of 1812 and Maria VAn Schaick. Eloise Carpenter Wickham graduated from Smith College. She had one brother, Charles Mayhew Carpenter who married Mary Alice Hendy of Cynthiana, Ky. They had two children Alvin Rich and Alice. When Charles and Mary Alice divorced Alice stayed with her mother and Charles returned to Binghamton to live with his aunt and uncle. Alvin graduated from Cornell in 1928..
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Carpenter-Mayhew papers include correspondence, pamphlets, photographs, legal and estate papers, photographs, and clippings relating to Alvin R. Carpenter, Alice Carpenter, Charles Mayhew, Eloise Carpenter Wickham, and Robert Sloane Wickham. Charles Mayhew Carpenter papers include personal and business correspondence, 1910-1918, including letters from his estranged wife Mary.
Oversized items include DeRidder family slave indentures, commissions, officers' roll of Col. Walter DeRidder's Regiment, New York State Militia; Abiel W. Mayhew commission, Columbia Light Infantry, 1809; certificates and diplomas.
Bound volumes include Catherine S. DeRidder travel diary, 1877; Eloise Wickham account books, 1932-1937; Robert S. Wickham physics notebook, n.d.; album of original drawings by Anne E. Allaben for Robert S. Wickham's book, A Saratoga Boyhood, with final proofs.and book of reviews of A Saratoga Boyhood. Robert Wickham's photograph albums depicting hiking, camping, hunting, and fishing in the Adirondacks, 4 volumes, 1905-1949, with negatives. Another Robert Wickham album depicting family photos, ca. 1860-1956. Also Charles Mayhew Carpenter photographs of family members, houses, and scenes, ca. 1900-1914; a carte-de-visit album, probably Alvin and Alida Carpenter; Eloise Wickham school exercises, n.d.; Regimental record book with orders, muster rolls, and returns, Simon DeRidder, 1812; and various published books and pamphlets.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wickham, Robert Sloane, 1877-; Allaben, Anne E.; Carpenter family.; Carpenter, Alice.; Carpenter, Alvin Rich.; Carpenter, Charles Mayhew.; DeRidder family.; DeRidder, Catherine s.; DeRidder, Walter.; Mayhew family.; Wickham family.; Wickham, Eloise Carpenter.; New York State. Militia.
Subjects:
Family -- New York (State) -- Binghamton; Family -- New York (State) -- Saratoga Springs.; Family -- New York (State) -- Schuylerville.; Slavery -- New York (State)
Places:
Adirondack Mountains (N.Y.) -- Description and travel.; Adirondack Mountains (N.Y.); United States -- History -- War of 1812.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Back Log Camp, Sabael, N.Y., 1896-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Pamphlets, 1946-50 and n.d. Includes a history, 1896-1946, a map, 1950 greetings, 1950 general information and rules, and two copies of a much earlier pamphlet, The Back Log Idea.
- Carpenter, Alice., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Letter, n.d., to “papa.”
- Carpenter, Alonzo B., Schuylerville., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Cabinet photograph.
- Carpenter, Alvin R. I., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Estate papers, 1914
- Carpenter, Alvin R. I., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Letter sent, 1914.
- Carpenter, Alvin R. II., 1914-16, 95 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Letters received, 1914-16 and 1995. Most of the early letters were set by his mother, Mary (Hendy) Carpenter, or his sister, Alice Carpenter, while they were apart due to his parents’ separation.
- Carpenter, Alvin R. II., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Letters sent, 1917 and n.d. A letter to “Mrs. Landon” written at Oak Street School, 1917, apparently a class exercise; and an undated note to “papa” while he was still with his mother, opening with “I am verry lonesome with out you.”
- Carpenter, Betty, Tulsa, Okla, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Letter sent, 1964, to Eloise (Carpenter) Wickham; family news.
- Carpenter family., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Photograph, unmounted, of Alice and Alvin Carpenter.
- Carpenter, Mary (Hendy)., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Letters received, 1914, on insurance matters.
- DeRidder family., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Genealogical notes; a memo, “Who is Who,” by C[atherine] S. DeRidder, Memorial Day, 1905; and a letter, George W. DeRidder, Ballston Spa, to Eloise (Carpenter) Wickham, Binghamton, 15 November 1905.
- Hendy family., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letter, N.F. McClure, Washington, D.C., to Alvin R. Carpenter, Binghamton, 26 May 1941, enclosing a typescript of a genealogical supplement of the Hendy family of Kentucky.
- Mayhew, Charles W., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Engraving of his residence, Schuylerville, N.Y. It appears, without the full margins, facing p. 260 of Nathaniel B. Sylvester, History of Saratoga County, N.Y. (Philadelphia: Everts and Ensign, 1878).
- Mayhew, Charles W., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Cabinet photograph, inscribed by the sitter to “my dear neice Alice,” 1901.
- Mayhew, Charles W., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Resolution in memory of CMM, late president, Saratoga Victory Manufacturing Company.
- Mayhew family., 1956-67 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Correspondence about the family plot in Prospect Hill Cemetery, Schuylerville, 1956-67, including a plot plan and inscriptions.
- Saturday Study Club, Schuylerville, N.Y., 1901-02 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Minutes
- Shakespeare Dramatic Club, Binghamton, N.Y., 1956-67 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Miscellaneous materials, including “Constitution and By-laws / 19567-1957,” along with other materials accumulated by Eloise (Carpenter) Wickham, including a newspaper photograph of her as a founding member on its 45th anniversary.
- Wickham, Alan R., 1963-67 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Letters sent, 1963-67, to Eloise (Carpenter) Wickham, except for one of 1967 sent to Mr. and Mrs. Alvin R. Carpenter; family news.
- Wickham, Carolyn., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Letter sent to Ruth Everett, 1965.
- Mayhew family., 1901 (Box 1, Folder Not Received)
  An issue of The Genealogical Advertiser, vol. 4, no. 1 (March 1901), containing an article, “English Ancestry of Governor Thomas Mayhew.”
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter).Business papers, 1947-65 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Cards received.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1966-67 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Estate papers, 1966-67. Includes legal papers; an exchange of letters between Conrad and Lucy Meinecke, Springville, N.Y. with Alvin and Betty Carpenter, Binghamton, N,Y, 1967, in reference to Alan Wickham’s financial irresponsibility; with a 1961 appraisal of the family residence at 129 Murray Street, including a Polaroid photograph.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  “Hospital mail,” 1966.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1914-41 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Letters received, 1914-41.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1963-65 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Letters received, 1963-65.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1951-66 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Medical documents, 1951-66.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1946-64 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Newspaper clippings, 1946-64, relating to the Monday Afternoon Club, the Shakespeare Dramatic Club and other theatrical events, politics, etc.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1982-89 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  School exercises, Schuylerville Union Free School, 1882-89.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1982-89 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  School reports, Schuylerville Union Free School, 1882-89.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1901-02 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Papers prepared for the Saturday Study Club, Schuylerville, 1901-02
- Wickham family, Ballston Spa, N.Y., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Photograph marked “Bob Wickham’s baby sister.”
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., 1912 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  “Biographical Sketch of the National Progressive Party’s nominee for Broome County Judge and Surrogate.” Pamphlet, n.d. [?1912] 2 pp. Contains a biography of the subject along with useful biographical data on his father, Charles H. Wickham.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., 1917-58 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Financial papers, 1917-58; includes record of income, 1917-25; status, 1956; and utility recapitulation, 1957-58.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Law licenses.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Medical papers.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., 1893-96 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Pre-academic certificates, Saratoga Springs Union School, 1893-96.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Woodcraft materials, clipped from newspapers and magazines.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane and Eloise (Carpenter)., 1928-70 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Ephemera, 1928-70. Includes church bulletins from Trinity Memorial Church (Episcopal), Binghamton; insurance policies; junk mail; and unclassifiable material. An important item is “My constant prayer,” in the hand of RSW.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane and Eloise (Carpenter)., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Photographs.
- Business, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Personal, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Personal, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Personal, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Business, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Personal, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Business, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Personal, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Business, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Personal, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Business, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Personal, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Business, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bankbooks and other records, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Allaben Drawings, n.d. (Box 4, Volume 1)
  “Original Sketches of Miss Anne E. Allaben for ‘A Saratoga Boyhood’ by Robert S. Wickham. (Final proofs of all plates made therefrom opposite.)” Scrapbook with pencil drawings and photo prints pasted in. A 2 pp. carbon copy of a review by Arthur C. Parker of Naples, N,Y. [a prominent Seneca and archaeologist retired from the Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences] is laid in.
- Adirondack League Club, 1893 (Box 5, Volume 1)
  Constitution, by-laws, rules, membership list, annual report, list of allotments with surveys and floor plans. No Carpenter or Mayhew is listed, nor any resident of Saratoga Springs; the club was three years old,
- An Act, to Organize the Militia of the State of New-York, Passed April 21, 1818. Albany: J.W. Clark, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Amendments to the Militia Law, Passed March 13, 1821. Albany: Websters and Skinners, n,d, 1821 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Marked in ink “Simon DeRidder,” along with pp. 7-10 of another copy marked “Walter DeRidder.”
- Annual Register of the United States Naval Academy at Annapolis, Md. 1875-76. Washington: Government Printing Office, 1875 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Laws of New-York: viz. An Act, to amend an Act, entitled “an Act to organize the Militia of this State”... Albany: J. Buel, [1814], 1814 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Incomplete.
- Official Register of the Officers and Midshipmen of the United States Naval Academy. Newport, Rhode Island. Nov. 1st, 1864. Newport: Frederick A. Pratt, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  The list of midshipmen forming the fourth class of 1864 (p. 23) includes Alvin R. Carpenter from “Texas.” He initialed inside front cover, and made notes about the fate of his classmates. A pamphlet, “Regulations Governing the Admission of Candidates into the Naval Academy,” is inside the front cover.
- To the Republican Electors of the State of New-York, 1814? (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Pamphlet, uncut
- The Book of Common Prayer. London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1900 (Box 5, Volume 8)
  Pocket format. Inscribed on flyleaf: “Robert S. Wickham / Binghamton / N.Y.”
- Wickham, Robert S., Binghamton, N.Y., n.d. (Box 5, Volume 9)
  A Saratoga Boyhood, wrapped and tied for mailing.
- Wickham, Robert S., June 1998 (Box 5)
  Class of 1928 75th Reunion paperweight for Most Cornell Descendants
- Wickham, Robert S., 1998 (Box 5)
  Class of 1928 65th Reunion medal
- Ansco Company, Binghamton, N.Y., 1915 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Blueprints, two sheets, 1915.
- Carpenter, Alvin R. II., 1928-42 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Certificates, 1928-42 and n.d. Includes a swimming certificate from Cornell, diplomas and certifications, and a tribute upon retirement.
- DeRidder family., 1800's (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Papers. Included are two slave indentures, 1827; commencement program, Union College, 1818; two commissions, Walter DeRidder, 1818, and another, 1819; “An Oration on Noses,” n,d,; several documents on the division of WDR’s estate, 1832; letter, E.H. Dixon, House of Refuge, to Jacob Deridder, “Opposite Schuylervile, “1832, on the occasion of Walter’s death; deed, Jesse Chatfield to Kilian DeRidder, 1776; officers’ roll of Col. Walter DeRidder’s Regiment, New York State Militia; and a small receipt for eggs and silk hose.
- Mayhew, Abiel W., 1809 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Commission, Columbia County Light Infantry, 1809.
- Schuylerville Standard., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Issue of June 11, 1914 with front-page obituary of Alvin R, Carpenter; four copies.
- Wickham, Alan R., 1929 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Diploma, Binghamton Junior High Schools, 1929.
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1889 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Diploma, Schuylerville Union School, 1889.
- Wickham, Robert Sloane., 1896 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Diploma, Saratoga Springs Union Free School, 1896.
- Carpenter, Charles Mayhew., 1912 (Box 7, Volume 1)
  Builder’s Estimate and Time Book, 1912. Only one week was used, for 11 March 1912 at 1134 West 37 Drive, apparently in greater Los Angeles. Seven workers’ hours are recorded including “CMC” and “Hirashima.”
- DeRidder, C[atherine] S., 1887-88 (Box 7, Volume 2)
  Diary of her European travels “with brother” from December 25, 1877 to July 16, 1878. Slipped in are clipped engravings and clippings, apparently of sites visited: Eaton Hall, Hotel and Pension de l’Ours at Grindelwald, Grand Hotel Pension Bellevue au Lac Zurich, Hotel du Nord, Coeln, and Hotel Monet, Vevey.
- DeRidder, C[atherine] S., 1887 (Box 7, Volume 3)
  Partial copy of the previous item.
- DeRidder, Walter [?]., 1835 (Box 7, Volume 4)
  Commonplace book, 1835, with transaction entries of a farmer. Difficult to decipher; commodities include eggs, apples, pork, ham; there is a reference to “Troy and Champlain ofice” and another to “wish to draw wood Cambrge.”
- Mayhew, Ida C., Victory Mills, N.Y., 1862 (Box 7, Volume 5)
  Exercise book, Maplewood Institute, Pittsfield, Mass., 9 October 1862, later used as a clipping book, with newspaper items dated 1862 to 1873. Inside cover is a photograph inscribed “Maplewood Hotel / Pittsfield / Mass / Formerly Maplewood Institute.”
- Wickham, Eloise (Carpenter)., 1932-37 (Box 7, Volume 6)
  Account book, 1932-37, of household and personal expenditures at item level. Inside cover is a membership list of a professional women’s organization, the “New York Epsilon Athenians – Binghamton, N.Y.”
- Wickham, Robert S., n.d. (Box 7, Volume 7)
  Physics notebook, n.d., probably used at Saratoga Springs High School, but possibly at Cornell.
- Wickham, Robert S., 1948 (Box 7, Volume 8)
  Book of reviews, letters, etc. of A Saratoga Boyhood (1948), including a short errata (p. 4) and a fine letter (p. 5) from Frances Steloff in which she comments that she was the “official flower girl” in Saratoga until she left for Boston in 1900. A press release and an order blank are slipped in.
- “Aunt Fanny.” Night Cap Stories. Boston: Estes and Lauriat, 1895 (Box 8, Volume 1)
  Inscribed inside front cover: “To Alvin / From / Georgina / Merry Xmas / 1914.”
- An Impartial Narrative of the Most Important Engagements Which Took Place Between His Majesty’s Forces and the Rebels, During the Irish Rebellion, 1798 (Box 8, Volume 2)
  First American Edition. Cambridge, N,Y: Tennery and Stockwell, n.d. Inscribed “Simon DeRidder” on p. 3.
- Luce. S.B. Seamanship. New York: D. Van Nostrand, 1863 (Box 8, Volume 3)
  Inscribed in ink on flyleaf: “A.R. Carpenter / Midshipman / U.S.N. / 1864.” Covers missing
- Redfield, Henry S. Civil Procedure. Selected Pleadings. No. I. Cornell University College of Law, n.d. (Box 8, Volume 4)
  Inscribed on cover: “Robert Sloane Wickham.”
- Class 1864-1868 / United States Naval Academy / The Fiftieth Anniversary, 1864-1868 (Box 8, Volume 5, 6)
  Pamphlet, two copies.
- Album, 1905-19 (Box 9, Volume 1)
  Mounted in traditional oblong albums with black pages, these photos document half a century of hiking, tenting, hunting and fishing in the Adirondacks, along with some domestic views in Schuylerville, and some vacation shots. There is considerable identification: year of shot, place, some people. Some other items such as obituaries are tipped in. The fourth album is primarily of family members.
- Album, 1917-23 (Box 9, Volume 2)
- Album, 1923-38 (Box 10, Volume 1)
- Album, 1939-49 (Box 10, Volume 2)
- Karl B Stickley, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Negatives for albums in boxes 9-10. “Karl B. Stickley” [hereafter KBS], 59 Carroll Street Marked in pencil “1916” 1-5 prints 6-38 negatives
- “Camp Roosevelt / Oteyokwa Lake, Pa.”, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Marked in pencil “Best East Inlet hunting trip 1919 films – McComb, etc.” 1-6 negatives
- “Austin S. Bump” [hereafter ASB], 180 Washington Street, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Rubber stamped “AUG 6 1920” 1-5 prints 6-11 negatives
- Photo envelope with no identification, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  1-2 prints 3-13 negatives Notes: 5, curious wooden church; 8, automobile
- 1922 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Marked in pencil “Niagara et al 1922” 1-67 negatives Notes: 18, curious wooden church; 57-58, “Spirit of Life,” Saratoga Springs
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Marked in pencil “1923”’ 1-11 negatives
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Marked in pencil “1923” 1-8 negatives
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Marked in pencil “1923”’ 1-38 negatives
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Marked in pencil “1923” 1-33 negatives
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Marked In pencil “Limekiln Falls / 1926” 1-6 negatives
- Robert S. Wickham, U.S. District Court, Binghamton, 1929 and 1930 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  1-29 negatives Notes: 29, dog
- Plain envelope, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  1-27 negatives
- Robert S. Wickham, U.S. District Court, Binghamton, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Marked in pencil “Otter Brook trip 1932” 1-3 prints 4-13 negatives
- KBS, art deco envelope, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Marked in pencil “1938” “A. Wickham” and rubber stamped “AUG 3 193[ ]” 1-2 prints 3-24 negatives Notes: 1, marked “Beaver Lake” and stamped “SEP 1 1938”; 2, stamped same
- “Randall’s Photo Finishing Service / Binghamton Savings Bank”, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  No markings 1-13 negatives Notes: 7-12 seem to be on a cruise; 10 bears signs “Ferry to Inverrurie – Belmont” and “Apothecaries Hall” [perhaps in Aberdeen, Scotland]
- Stickley’s Certified Art Prints, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  1-9 negatives
- ASB, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  Marked on reverse “Ford / Knickerbocker / 19 St. Charles Place” 1-25 prints 26-28 negatives Notes: 13, 3 copies with marking from negative, Doc”; 14, marking from negative “Boom” (shows a cannon); 15-17, caricatures identified of immediate family; 20, “A Dead Dog”
- ASB, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  Stamped “SEP 15 1920” 1-10 prints 11 negative Notes: 1-2, curious church; 11, negative of same
- ASB, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  No markings 1-10 negatives
- ASB, JUL 20 1920 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  Marked on reverse “Moses Lake / Quaker Lake” and stamped JUL 20 1920” 1-6 prints 7-11 negatives
- ASB, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  No markings, but license plate on automobile reads 1920 1-28 prints 29-34 negatives
- Plain envelope, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  No markings 1-11 prints
- Envelope printed “Mrs. Robert S. Wickham”, c.1890 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  No markings 1-5 prints 6-8 negatives Notes: 1, marked on reverse “Helen Colclazer” (appears to be a c.1890 print); 2, marked “Eloise Cameron Carpenter” with photographer imprint “George W. Conkey / Glens Falls” (baby photo); 36, Saratoga Monument
- KBS, 59 Carroll Street, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  Marked in pencil “Discards” 1 print 2-61 negatives Notes: 1, man with backpack; 2, Ondawa Hotel [Schroon Lake]; 3, motor stage; 4, building with sign “Homemade Candy”
- KBS, Art Deco envelope, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  1 print 2-30 negatives
- KBS, 59 Carroll Street, 1917 (Box 14-15, Folder 26)
  No markings, but license plate on automobile reads 1917 1-93 negatives Notes: 4, abovementioned auto; 46, interior of cabin; 50, hotel, perhaps AuSable Club; 64, cabin; 68, house; 81, interior; 86, five women on a porch; 88-89, dog portrait; 90,93, boy on city street; 91, girl on city street
- KBS, 47 Carroll Street, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  No markings 1-5 prints 6-46 negatives Notes: 12, auto; 13, David Henderson monument near Tahawus; 19-20, hiking with packs; 29, city street; 34, building with sign “Trading Post”
- Plain brown envelope, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  Marked in ink with RSW’s print order 1-11 negatives
- RSW, 47 Carroll Street, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  No markings 1-9 prints 10-19 negatives
- RSW, 47 Carroll Street, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  No markings 1-26 negatives
- RSW, Art Deco envelope, SEP 1 1938 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  Rubber stamped “SEP 1 1938” 1-2 negatives
- Carpenter and Symmes Coalyard, c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Unmounted prints taken by a competent amateur, with a few mounted and/or professional photographs, as follows:
- Carpenter family. 14 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Mary (Hendy), Alvin R. II, and Alice Carpenter.
- Churches. 6 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Mostly American Gothic stone buildings.vvvvvvvvvvv
- Houses. 11 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Some are family homes, some historic houses.
- Outdoor scenes and genre. 19 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Includes baseball and football games, Asian circus performers, vehicles, and several interiors.
- Overseas. 8 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Views probably in Great Britain.
- People. 32 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Chiefly groups; unidentified.
- Scenery. 24 items., c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Probably unidentifiable, many with water, possibly the Hudson.
- Street views. 6 items, c.1900-14 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  Includes Congress Park, streetcar, overturned railroad car, village from above, and a substantial school building.